<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sammyette's blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/</link><description>Recent content on sammyette's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 21:06:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching from Spotify to Local Music</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/switching-from-spotify-to-local-music/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 21:06:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/switching-from-spotify-to-local-music/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I mentioned in one of my posts before, I like listening to music. Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t?
I have it in the background while working on a project, I jam to it while bored
or just have it playing so my environment won&amp;rsquo;t be completely silent.
&amp;hellip;Except when you get interrupted by an ad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spotify, and others like YouTube Music or Deezer are all pretty cool,
but they have ads (besides YT) unless you pay for a monthly subscription service.
Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like paying for Spotify premium &lt;em>just&lt;/em> to not have ads,
so I stopped using it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
>
&lt;a href="https://modeus.is-inside.me/TREhttCz.png" >
&lt;img src="https://modeus.is-inside.me/TREhttCz.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="A view of my local music library">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>A view of my local music library&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
For music that I like (which is mostly what I listen to) I downloaded and properly
tagged all of them (some manually). The perks of this is no ads (obviously) and
offline listening. I can also sync this between my phone easily, as my music is just
on my Google Drive. As I&amp;rsquo;m not an audiophile and don&amp;rsquo;t want music taking &lt;em>that much&lt;/em>
storage, I have them in 124kbps MP3 or M4A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A con to this is having to host all of this. Going my route with the quality
and format, it&amp;rsquo;ll take a LOT of music to reach Google Drive&amp;rsquo;s free tier of 15GB
storage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve always downloaded my favourites, which is mostly kpop but I decided to take
a pretty much full time switch away from Spotify. A question you may ask is about music
discovery. If you only have a local library, how do you find new music to listen to?
To answer that question, YouTube and osu are the ways of how I get new music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>YouTube is definitely a great place to get a very wide variety of music, as there is
independent artists, meme songs and whatever that aren&amp;rsquo;t on services like Spotify.
A good example is &lt;em>Maid with Dragons,&lt;/em> the season 2 opening song of &lt;em>Miss Kobayashi&amp;rsquo;s
Dragon Maid.&lt;/em> Of course, I can download this from YouTube instead with youtube-dl.
The reason I also mentioned osu is that because it&amp;rsquo;s a rhythm game, and I find a lot
of random but good maps (and therefore songs) and I can definitely say that
it has helped in finding a lot of good music. This is how I discovered Ashnikko,
currently a personal favourite with her type of music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you only really listen to music once in a while, and/or just the stuff you like,
I recommend going the local approach or using YouTube, and if you need a rich presence
kinda like Spotify&amp;rsquo;s, &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/TorchedSammy/Clematis" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Clematis&lt;/a> has you
covered.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emptiness</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/emptiness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 12:37:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/emptiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of people wish that they could have free time to do whatever they want,
that being playing some games or catching up on a TV series. On the other hand,
I wish that I could be occupied with more things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I am still a student, having to deal with a few online classes in the week,
I have a lot of free time to code things or play games. The thing is though that I
find a lot of the games I used to play to be boring now, and I can&amp;rsquo;t be coding literally
everyday since that&amp;rsquo;s gonna get boring as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me, this is where a lingering feeling of emptiness comes from. If I&amp;rsquo;m not
playing games or working on a project, I&amp;rsquo;m basically just idling on Discord
bored out of my mind with nothing to do. Life feels boring and not that fun.
A lot of this feeling comes from lack of motivation that I mentioned
&lt;a class="link" href="https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>in a previous post&lt;/a> and feeling like an annoyance
in the Discord servers I am in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like sharing things, sometimes too much. Not too much as in personal matters as
there isn&amp;rsquo;t anything going on in my personal life but a lot of things that I find
or like to talk about and I frequently feel like I am a pest that no one likes.
Usually if I mention this in places as well, anyone trying to comfort or help
doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel genuine at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would really rather just lay in bed all day and think about nothing. After all,
I mostly feel like nothing but a person no one cares about and someone who tries
to be liked while still being disliked. I still want to be productive, I even
made a short post about it but it only helps when I want to work on a project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever since this pandemic started and everyone&amp;rsquo;s been forced to stay at home,
I realized how boring my life is. it&amp;rsquo;s why I sometimes do crave for attention
or acknowledgement, recognition, anything at all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Organization &amp; Scheduling</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/organization-scheduling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 23:07:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/organization-scheduling/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the most part, I try to be as organized as possible. There&amp;rsquo;s times where I
just don&amp;rsquo;t bother at all, but the way that I layout my things are pretty organized.
Despite this, I actually don&amp;rsquo;t have a formal schedule for myself. I do have some
sort of routine of course, but I&amp;rsquo;ll do things during the day at pretty much any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A friend of mine is very scheduled on their anime watching. An entire spreadsheet
for the year of what to watch, on what day and the episode. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can
reach to that level of proper scheduling. I definitely do want to make a schedule
of what I&amp;rsquo;ll do during the week, that being working projects or idling on Discord,
or watching anime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of schedules is sleep schedule. For the past few weeks, I have been going
to sleep at around 11:30pm or 12am and waking up at 7:45am. I do want to fix
this to get more sleep (maybe an hour earlier, 10pm) but it isn&amp;rsquo;t an actual problem
for me right now. A method to sleep better is the 90 minute sleep cycle. For the time
that I want to wake up, track back 90 minutes each to the closest time that I intend
to go to bed. I saw this idea from a YouTube video and thought it would work &lt;em>decently&lt;/em>
so I&amp;rsquo;ll try it eventually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back to organization. I recently tagged a bunch of my music so that I can import into
cmus and for the sake of consistency. YouTube won&amp;rsquo;t have any metadata tags, and
download websites vary. It takes effort to do these things but makes sure that everything
looks nice and of course organized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In having a schedule, you&amp;rsquo;re most likely gonna be an organized person and that is the
next step that I want to take.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Productivity</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/productivity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 21:10:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/productivity/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like looking at statistics sometimes. Charts, graphs or whatever, they look nice. This is why
I semi-frequently look at my &lt;a class="link" href="https://wakatime.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Wakatime&lt;/a> dashboard. Wakatime has actually
made me a bit more productive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I set a daily goal of coding 4 hours or more everyday. The only times I can take a break on this is
when I don&amp;rsquo;t code in the day at all, like just to chill on Discord or watch a kdrama.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started 2 new projects in this week: &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/TorchedSammy/Clematis" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Clematis&lt;/a> and
&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/TorchedSammy/Nerine" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Nerine&lt;/a>. So while working on either of these, I have to
code for 4 hours at least. This has basically forced me a bit to be less lazy and to avoid putting
off fixing bugs and adding features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing about Wakatime is that you can also choose to be competitive by coding a lot. It has a global
public leaderboard with tons of people putting tens of hours a day just programming stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t think
that I can reach to that point, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;d be idling in my text editor trying to get time up, which
is least productive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to compete against me in coding, I am willing to make a leaderboard, but you also have to
join my Discord server at the left.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kdramas</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/kdramas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:22:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/kdramas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good entertainment for me is thrilling (melo)drama. I mentioned in one of my previous
posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching &lt;em>What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Secretary Kim?&lt;/em> and it&amp;rsquo;s a romance
drama. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished watching it yet, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing posts
for this blog and playing retro games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A show that I have been keeping up with is
&lt;a class="link" href="https://mydramalist.com/698835-second-husband" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;em>The Second Husband&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s episode
length is 30mins so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to digest but has 120 episodes total. &lt;em>Second Husband&lt;/em>
is an interesting story since it is a revenge drama that has romance in it. The series
starts off a bit slow, but progressively gets addicting and wondering what will happen
in the next episode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first drama was &lt;a class="link" href="https://mydramalist.com/21308-mother" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;em>Mother&lt;/em>&lt;/a> which is also a very
interesting story about child abuse and what it really means to be a mother. Anytime
someone asks for drama recommendations, I always say this first since it hit me so
differently compared to others I&amp;rsquo;ve watched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve also watched the adaptation of &lt;em>True Beauty&lt;/em> and even while I&amp;rsquo;ve read the source
manhwa I still enjoyed it like I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly I just wanted to shill &lt;em>Second Husband&lt;/em> as it&amp;rsquo;s a drama that I am currently
enjoying &lt;strong>a lot&lt;/strong> and I&amp;rsquo;m always impatient waiting for the weekend to watch the latest
5 episodes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Like Kpop (and other non-English music)</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/why-i-like-kpop-and-other-non-english-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 19:36:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/why-i-like-kpop-and-other-non-english-music/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like listening to music, it&amp;rsquo;s easy and accessible. Unlike video media where I
have to actually pay attention, I can play music in the background and jam out.
What type of music do I listen to? I listen to what sounds good to me. But I do
have specific genres I like, one of them being kpop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Immediate reaction for the average person (when you read the title) is that
&amp;ldquo;kpop bad, not good music u dont even understand what theyre saying.&amp;rdquo;
First thing I want to point out is that almost all music is subjective in their
quality (I guess if we ignore lyricism and whether that&amp;rsquo;s top quality) so you not
liking this piece of music doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second point of it being another language is arguably a &lt;em>semi&lt;/em> reasonable point.
I can bet that for most people when they listen to music, they don&amp;rsquo;t exactly pay
attention to what is actually being sung but more just how everything sounds. This
is the way (and the only way) I judge music for the most part. I&amp;rsquo;m not a music critique
so I do not have to analyze.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>stan&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Stan is a mix of stalker and fan. Its a crazy fan who basically worships a celebrity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A separate reason would be kpop &lt;em>stans&lt;/em>. In my opinion, an average stan isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually that crazy, but the very loud and vocal minority are those crazy fans that
stalk idols. I don&amp;rsquo;t identify as a stan of any type, since I listen to music very casually,
but this is one of the other reasons why people don&amp;rsquo;t like the music, which is because
of them and the bad side of the community. The thing about music communities though
is that they can basically be ignored, and you can just go through the discography
of a group or idol to figure out what you&amp;rsquo;ll like. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a fair bit of people
who were put off by the music while they haven&amp;rsquo;t even heard anything simply because
of these people, and once I introduced them to some of my favourites they realized
that they liked it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first kpop song I listened to was Gangnam Style. Officially, it&amp;rsquo;s almost everyone&amp;rsquo;s
first kpop song. But my actual first is &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nnVjsos40qk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;em>Secret Story of the Swan&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.
I was in a Discord music channel, and it came up. I thought that it sounded really good,
so I looked at what was playing then looked at the group&amp;rsquo;s other music. From then is how
I discovered music from LOONA, Red Velvet and all the other popular groups. If you
need some recommendations, join my community Discord at the left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good music to me is what sounds good. Language pretty much doesn&amp;rsquo;t take any part of it.
Music from other places of the world also brings even more variety to my playlist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fostering a Discord Community</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/fostering-a-discord-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:25:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/fostering-a-discord-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like owning and managing Discord communities. I enjoy bringing people together and
making a hub for people to chat. I&amp;rsquo;ve moderated a few Discord servers before, and
even owned one myself with 500 members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though in real life I am very introverted and not that social, in the online
world I kinda like talking to people (with similar interests of course) which is
why I enjoy managing servers, since staff members would be the ones with most
interaction with the community at large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So my server with 500 members. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen servers at ~4k members which weren&amp;rsquo;t as active
as my previous server. That place basically never died, which made it hard to moderate
since I actually sleep and was basically the only staff. It was a good place, I still
have one of the members as a Discord friend (I should really talk to them again&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happened was kinda weird and I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the details (or cared to) but
as the server expanded, it got more inactive, I opened staff applications and
interacted less. I don&amp;rsquo;t really remember why I did this besides school, but I still
could&amp;rsquo;ve been there after a school day was finished. But a part of the active members
of the server started to dislike me a bit, created their own server and separated
from the community. At that point I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to manage it anymore,
so I just passed ownership to someone who I gave an admin position.
That was a dumb decision since a couple days later the server was just gone.
Out of existence, deleted. Community that I put a sum of effort into pretty much
disappeared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me transferring ownership wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the point of not wanting to associate with
that place anymore, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t want the &amp;ldquo;owner&amp;rdquo; position anymore. I remember
sending a message to that admin as to why they deleted it but don&amp;rsquo;t remember what they
said or any conversation. So of the members that created their server, the one I had
added as a friend gave an invite and I talked to the others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s all I remember about that story of my server owner life. Lasted a couple
months. I always tried to make an active community after that with the same feel
as the original but it was never there, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even grow it to past 50 members.
Between that, I also had a separate server for announcing personal project news
and a side chat place (it was dead). At the start of 2021, I started being more active
on GitHub. I worked on my Stardew Valley mod manager, some Node.js packages and other
things. In between that, I decided to migrate my mini &amp;ldquo;community&amp;rdquo; and announcement
Discord to a newer different place, since I thought that making a new server and doing
a migration would be easier than changing around my old server. The intention would be
that the server would be a better community place to finally have a chat place decent chat
place. Unfortunately, It was yet again a dead place with once in a while messages. I didn&amp;rsquo;t
really mind it that much though, since I was active in the r/unixporn Discord server.
In mid-March, I started development on Hilbish. My biggest project, and my longest living
one (more than 2 months!). Since it has semi-frequent version releases, I revamped
my server a bit and added specific news and software update ping roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I basically got burnt out around July and stopped making commits on Hilbish until the
middle of September. That was when I decided to make yet another revamp to my Discord
server to make it a bit better for a generalized community server. This server right now
is the &lt;a class="link" href="https://discord.gg/3PDdcQz" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>cloud community&lt;/a>. With only 26 people while I&amp;rsquo;m writing,
it&amp;rsquo;s still a decently active community place even at that low member count.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized that to have a healthy or active community server, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to have
20,000+ members. You just need a few frequently chatting people. I made a hoisted role
for active people, started saying more myself in there and put an advert in my Discord
bio. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got the 26 members, from about 10.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Motivation and Self-esteem</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem/</guid><description>&lt;p>I sometimes wonder how people keep motivated to work on projects or do certain
things. I&amp;rsquo;m basically just a hobbyist software developer who&amp;rsquo;s not that well known.
Motivation to do things has been the only problem for me for the past few months
or even the (year).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Rosettea/Hilbish" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Hilbish&lt;/a> is my biggest project, which is just
a simple shell stitched together with Lua and a sh interpreter with an API. The only
reason I am keeping it updated for the most part is because I personally use Hilbish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people make things for themselves, just put it on GitHub and make an update
when they wish. I&amp;rsquo;m the same also, but it gets tiring after you don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore
but still wanna code and work on it.
As an example, &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/TorcedSammy/Ceta" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Ceta&lt;/a> is a Stardew Valley
mod manager. It has about 8 bug issues open and hasn&amp;rsquo;t received a feature commit
for about half the year. I always feel like I want to go back to it, but I don&amp;rsquo;t
want to work on it while I&amp;rsquo;m not even using it or playing Stardew Valley with mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my opinion, keeping motivated ties into self-esteem a bit. If you feel like you
and your projects are worth anything for people besides you then it might be
a driving force to work on it, since you maybe want to keep them and talk about it
or that they suggest good features and enhancements to make so you want to add those
in. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have that much self-esteem, you may not feel it&amp;rsquo;s worth working on
the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing is maybe the fact of doing it by yourself (as in, sole maintainer).
I haven&amp;rsquo;t minded that for the past 2 years but as of now it&amp;rsquo;s a tiny bit depressing
while being stuck at home with too much free time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like writing code (even while not good) and creating things but I feel like I have
no reason to, so having someone doing that with me will definitely give a boost in
productivity. Just looking for the exact time when that can happen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 07:30:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like I should make a more general introduction post to tell more info
about myself. Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sammyette, if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell. Some people just call me sammy since it&amp;rsquo;s easier,
or TorchedSammy as that&amp;rsquo;s my username in some places (kinda want to change though).
I write code. It&amp;rsquo;s not good code at all, but it works and lately that is all
that I care about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides programming dumb things, I also watch TV shows like dramas and anime.
I have &lt;a class="link" href="https://myanimelist.net/profile/TorchedSammy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MyAnimeList&lt;/a> and
&lt;a class="link" href="https://mydramalist.com/profile/torchedsammy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MyDramaList&lt;/a> profiles linked.
As of now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching &lt;em>What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Secretary Kim&lt;/em> and it&amp;rsquo;s a
romantic comedy show which is a little bit dumb in a fun way.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched an anime in a while, and the last that I was looking at
was &lt;em>Ghost Stories&lt;/em> of all things primarily for the &amp;ldquo;so bad that it&amp;rsquo;s good&amp;rdquo;
English dub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any other free time I have when I&amp;rsquo;m not watching shows, I play some games.
These include Stardew Valley (which I plan to write about soon), Minecraft,
Teeworlds and anything that I have. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been enjoying playing these in
single player lately (also will write about).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can&amp;rsquo;t tell, I don&amp;rsquo;t write a lot in these. Honestly, a short blog is easier
to read and for me to write but when I have something that I definitely want to
rant about or enthusiastic about then it won&amp;rsquo;t be a minute read, so stay tuned
for that!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making a Blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/making-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 22:35:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/making-a-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, sammy here. A blog!&lt;br>
I decided to make a blog so I can put some of my random thoughts or do
a write up on something. Why? Why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be boring and kinda inactive but whatever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t notice, it&amp;rsquo;s made with Hugo since I thought that would be the
easiest to setup. I previously had my thoughts up &lt;a class="link" href="https://tilde.town/~sammyette/thoughts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>over here&lt;/a>
on tilde.town but this is easier to theme in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, welcome to my dumb blog!! Hope you enjoy my ramblings on things I don&amp;rsquo;t know about
and rants.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>