<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sammyette's blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/</link><description>Recent content on sammyette's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:25:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fostering a Discord Community</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/fostering-a-discord-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:25:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/fostering-a-discord-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like owning and managing Discord communities. I enjoy bringing people together and
making a hub for people to chat. I&amp;rsquo;ve moderated a few Discord servers before, and
even owned one myself with 500 members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though in real life I am very introverted and not that social, in the online
world I kinda like talking to people (with similar interests of course) which is
why I enjoy managing servers, since staff members would be the ones with most
interaction with the community at large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So my server with 500 members. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen servers at ~4k members which weren&amp;rsquo;t as active
as my previous server. That place basically never died, which made it hard to moderate
since I actually sleep and was basically the only staff. It was a good place, I still
have one of the members as a Discord friend (I should really talk to them again&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happened was kinda weird and I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the details (or cared to) but
as the server expanded, it got more inactive, I opened staff applications and
interacted less. I don&amp;rsquo;t really remember why I did this besides school, but I still
could&amp;rsquo;ve been there after a school day was finished. But a part of the active members
of the server started to dislike me a bit, created their own server and separated
from the community. At that point I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to manage it anymore,
so I just passed ownership to someone who I gave an admin position.
That was a dumb decision since a couple days later the server was just gone.
Out of existence, deleted. Community that I put a sum of effort into pretty much
disappeared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me transferring ownership wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the point of not wanting to associate with
that place anymore, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t want the &amp;ldquo;owner&amp;rdquo; position anymore. I remember
sending a message to that admin as to why they deleted it but don&amp;rsquo;t remember what they
said or any conversation. So of the members that created their server, the one I had
added as a friend gave an invite and I talked to the others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s all I remember about that story of my server owner life. Lasted a couple
months. I always tried to make an active community after that with the same feel
as the original but it was never there, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even grow it to past 50 members.
Between that, I also had a separate server for announcing personal project news
and a side chat place (it was dead). At the start of 2021, I started being more active
on GitHub. I worked on my Stardew Valley mod manager, some Node.js packages and other
things. In between that, I decided to migrate my mini &amp;ldquo;community&amp;rdquo; and announcement
Discord to a newer different place, since I thought that making a new server and doing
a migration would be easier than changing around my old server. The intention would be
that the server would be a better community place to finally have a chat place decent chat
place. Unfortunately, It was yet again a dead place with once in a while messages. I didn&amp;rsquo;t
really mind it that much though, since I was active in the r/unixporn Discord server.
In mid-March, I started development on Hilbish. My biggest project, and my longest living
one (more than 2 months!). Since it has semi-frequent version releases, I revamped
my server a bit and added specific news and software update ping roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I basically got burnt out around July and stopped making commits on Hilbish until the
middle of September. That was when I decided to make yet another revamp to my Discord
server to make it a bit better for a generalized community server. This server right now
is the &lt;a class="link" href="https://discord.gg/3PDdcQz" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>cloud community&lt;/a>. With only 26 people while I&amp;rsquo;m writing,
it&amp;rsquo;s still a decently active community place even at that low member count.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized that to have a healthy or active community server, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to have
20,000+ members. You just need a few frequently chatting people. I made a hoisted role
for active people, started saying more myself in there and put an advert in my Discord
bio. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got the 26 members, from about 10.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Motivation and Self-esteem</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem/</guid><description>&lt;p>I sometimes wonder how people keep motivated to work on projects or do certain
things. I&amp;rsquo;m basically just a hobbyist software developer who&amp;rsquo;s not that well known.
Motivation to do things has been the only problem for me for the past few months
or even the (year).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Rosettea/Hilbish" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Hilbish&lt;/a> is my biggest project, which is just
a simple shell stitched together with Lua and a sh interpreter with an API. The only
reason I am keeping it updated for the most part is because I personally use Hilbish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people make things for themselves, just put it on GitHub and make an update
when they wish. I&amp;rsquo;m the same also, but it gets tiring after you don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore
but still wanna code and work on it.
As an example, &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/TorcedSammy/Ceta" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Ceta&lt;/a> is a Stardew Valley
mod manager. It has about 8 bug issues open and hasn&amp;rsquo;t received a feature commit
for about half the year. I always feel like I want to go back to it, but I don&amp;rsquo;t
want to work on it while I&amp;rsquo;m not even using it or playing Stardew Valley with mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my opinion, keeping motivated ties into self-esteem a bit. If you feel like you
and your projects are worth anything for people besides you then it might be
a driving force to work on it, since you maybe want to keep them and talk about it
or that they suggest good features and enhancements to make so you want to add those
in. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have that much self-esteem, you may not feel it&amp;rsquo;s worth working on
the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing is maybe the fact of doing it by yourself (as in, sole maintainer).
I haven&amp;rsquo;t minded that for the past 2 years but as of now it&amp;rsquo;s a tiny bit depressing
while being stuck at home with too much free time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like writing code (even while not good) and creating things but I feel like I have
no reason to, so having someone doing that with me will definitely give a boost in
productivity. Just looking for the exact time when that can happen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 07:30:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like I should make a more general introduction post to tell more info
about myself. Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sammyette, if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell. Some people just call me sammy since it&amp;rsquo;s easier,
or TorchedSammy as that&amp;rsquo;s my username in some places (kinda want to change though).
I write code. It&amp;rsquo;s not good code at all, but it works and lately that is all
that I care about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides programming dumb things, I also watch TV shows like dramas and anime.
I have &lt;a class="link" href="https://myanimelist.net/profile/TorchedSammy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MyAnimeList&lt;/a> and
&lt;a class="link" href="https://mydramalist.com/profile/torchedsammy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MyDramaList&lt;/a> profiles linked.
As of now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching &lt;em>What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Secretary Kim&lt;/em> and it&amp;rsquo;s a
romantic comedy show which is a little bit dumb in a fun way.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched an anime in a while, and the last that I was looking at
was &lt;em>Ghost Stories&lt;/em> of all things primarily for the &amp;ldquo;so bad that it&amp;rsquo;s good&amp;rdquo;
English dub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any other free time I have when I&amp;rsquo;m not watching shows, I play some games.
These include Stardew Valley (which I plan to write about soon), Minecraft,
Teeworlds and anything that I have. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been enjoying playing these in
single player lately (also will write about).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can&amp;rsquo;t tell, I don&amp;rsquo;t write a lot in these. Honestly, a short blog is easier
to read and for me to write but when I have something that I definitely want to
rant about or enthusiastic about then it won&amp;rsquo;t be a minute read, so stay tuned
for that!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making a Blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/making-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 22:35:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/making-a-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, sammy here. A blog!&lt;br>
I decided to make a blog so I can put some of my random thoughts or do
a write up on something. Why? Why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be boring and kinda inactive but whatever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t notice, it&amp;rsquo;s made with Hugo since I thought that would be the
easiest to setup. I previously had my thoughts up &lt;a class="link" href="https://tilde.town/~sammyette/thoughts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>over here&lt;/a>
on tilde.town but this is easier to theme in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, welcome to my dumb blog!! Hope you enjoy my ramblings on things I don&amp;rsquo;t know about
and rants.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>