<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sammyette's blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/</link><description>Recent content on sammyette's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Motivation and Self-esteem</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/motivation-and-self-esteem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/motivation-and-self-esteem/</guid><description>&lt;p>I sometimes wonder how people keep motivated to work on projects or do certain
things. I&amp;rsquo;m basically just a hobbyist software developer who&amp;rsquo;s not that well known.
Motivation to do things has been the only problem for me for the past few months
or even the (year).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Rosettea/Hilbish" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Hilbish&lt;/a> is my biggest project, which is just
a simple shell stitched together with Lua and a sh interpreter with an API. The only
reason I am keeping it updated for the most part is because I personally use Hilbish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people make things for themselves, just put it on GitHub and make an update
when they wish. I&amp;rsquo;m the same also, but it gets tiring after you don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore
but still wanna code and work on it.
As an example, &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/TorcedSammy/Ceta" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Ceta&lt;/a> is a Stardew Valley
mod manager. It has about 8 bug issues open and hasn&amp;rsquo;t received a feature commit
for about half the year. I always feel like I want to go back to it, but I don&amp;rsquo;t
want to work on it while I&amp;rsquo;m not even using it or playing Stardew Valley with mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my opinion, keeping motivated ties into self-esteem a bit. If you feel like you
and your projects are worth anything for people besides you then it might be
a driving force to work on it, since you maybe want to keep them and talk about it
or that they suggest good features and enhancements to make so you want to add those
in. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have that much self-esteem, you may not feel it&amp;rsquo;s worth working on
the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing is maybe the fact of doing it by yourself (as in, sole maintainer).
I haven&amp;rsquo;t minded that for the past 2 years but as of now it&amp;rsquo;s a tiny bit depressing
while being stuck at home with too much free time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like writing code (even while not good) and creating things but I feel like I have
no reason to, so having someone doing that with me will definitely give a boost in
productivity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 07:30:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like I should make a more general introduction post to tell more info
about myself. Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sammyette, if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell. Some people just call me sammy since it&amp;rsquo;s easier,
or TorchedSammy as that&amp;rsquo;s my username in some places (kinda want to change though).
I write code. It&amp;rsquo;s not good code at all, but it works and lately that is all
that I care about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides programming dumb things, I also watch TV shows like dramas and anime.
I have &lt;a class="link" href="https://myanimelist.net/profile/TorchedSammy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MyAnimeList&lt;/a> and
&lt;a class="link" href="https://mydramalist.com/profile/torchedsammy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MyDramaList&lt;/a> profiles linked.
As of now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching &lt;em>What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Secretary Kim&lt;/em> and it&amp;rsquo;s a
romantic comedy show which is a little bit dumb in a fun way.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched an anime in a while, and the last that I was looking at
was &lt;em>Ghost Stories&lt;/em> of all things primarily for the &amp;ldquo;so bad that it&amp;rsquo;s good&amp;rdquo;
English dub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any other free time I have when I&amp;rsquo;m not watching shows, I play some games.
These include Stardew Valley (which I plan to write about soon), Minecraft,
Teeworlds and anything that I have. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been enjoying playing these in
single player lately (also will write about).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can&amp;rsquo;t tell, I don&amp;rsquo;t write a lot in these. Honestly, a short blog is easier
to read and for me to write but when I have something that I definitely want to
rant about or enthusiastic about then it won&amp;rsquo;t be a minute read, so stay tuned
for that!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making a Blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/making-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 22:35:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/making-a-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, sammy here. A blog!&lt;br>
I decided to make a blog so I can put some of my random thoughts or do
a write up on something. Why? Why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be boring and kinda inactive but whatever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t notice, it&amp;rsquo;s made with Hugo since I thought that would be the
easiest to setup. I previously had my thoughts up &lt;a class="link" href="https://tilde.town/~sammyette/thoughts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>over here&lt;/a>
on tilde.town but this is easier to theme in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, welcome to my dumb blog!! Hope you enjoy my ramblings on things I don&amp;rsquo;t know about
and rants.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>