<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on sammyette's blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on sammyette's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Motivation and Self-esteem</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/motivation-and-self-esteem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/motivation-and-self-esteem/</guid><description>I sometimes wonder how people keep motivated to work on projects or do certain things. I&amp;rsquo;m basically just a hobbyist software developer who&amp;rsquo;s not that well known. Motivation to do things has been the only problem for me for the past few months or even the (year).
Hilbish is my biggest project, which is just a simple shell stitched together with Lua and a sh interpreter with an API. The only reason I am keeping it updated for the most part is because I personally use Hilbish.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 07:30:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/introduction/</guid><description>I feel like I should make a more general introduction post to tell more info about myself. Hello!
I&amp;rsquo;m sammyette, if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell. Some people just call me sammy since it&amp;rsquo;s easier, or TorchedSammy as that&amp;rsquo;s my username in some places (kinda want to change though). I write code. It&amp;rsquo;s not good code at all, but it works and lately that is all that I care about.
Besides programming dumb things, I also watch TV shows like dramas and anime.</description></item><item><title>Making a Blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/making-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 22:35:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/posts/making-a-blog/</guid><description>Hello, sammy here. A blog!
I decided to make a blog so I can put some of my random thoughts or do a write up on something. Why? Why not?
It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be boring and kinda inactive but whatever.
If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t notice, it&amp;rsquo;s made with Hugo since I thought that would be the easiest to setup. I previously had my thoughts up over here on tilde.town but this is easier to theme in my opinion.</description></item></channel></rss>